

Via Privata Giancarlo Puecher, 9, 20127 Milano MI, Italy

□ (+886) 905-557-273 | 🗷 anchi.liu@mail.polimi.it | 🌴 tigercosmos.xyz | 🖸 tigercosmos | 🛅 liuanchi

Summary

Liu is a software engineer, and he is active in open source communities with the ID @tigercosmos. He is currently exchanging at Polytechnic University of Milan, and he is a master student of Computer Science at National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU), Taiwan. He holds a B.S. degree in Bio-Industrial Mechatronics Engineering from National Taiwan University (NTU) in 2019. His research interests mainly focus on system software and high-performance programming. He loves sharing. He teaches coding, writes articles, and gives talks. He participates in many open-source projects. He believes sharing makes the world a better place.

Education

Polytechnic University of Milan

Milan, Italy

M.S. EXCHANGE PROGRAM IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2021 - Aug. 2022

• The 1-year exchange program of NYCU.

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU)

Hsinchu, Taiwan

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2019 - Aug. 2022

- Thesis: Offloading Framework for Parallel Web Applications
 Previous school name: National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. IN BIO-INDUSTRIAL MECHATRONICS ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

Work Experience

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Hsinchu, Taiwan

TEACHING ASISTANCE

2019 - 2021

- · Parallel Programming (Spring 2021, Fall 2020) Won the best TA in the Institute of Computer Science
- Numerical Software Development (Fall 2020, Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- Compiler (Spring 2020)

National Center for High-Performance Computing

Hsinchu, Taiwan

RESEARCH INTERN

Jul 2020 – Mar 2021

- Built a full-stack system for neurual architechure search.
- · Researched on RDMA and SmartNICs.

Skymizer Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Feb 2019 - Jun 2019

· developed testing of C backed-end of the Open Neural Network Compiler (ONNC), including different level's unit tests.

developed testing of e backed that of the open neural network complet (office), metading different levels unit tests.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

CloudMosa, Inc.

Taipei, Taiwan Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Developing the module of "Download to Cloud" on Puffin Android, including three parts: (1) Connected the APIs of Dropbox, Google Drive, and Onedrive by Python, the cloud part, (2) Modified the protocols between the remote browser engine of Puffin, the server for cloud module and the Puffin Browser Client, the browser engine part, and (3) modified the Puffin Android for a new protocol of the engine, the browser client part
- Developing some parts of the header UI of Puffin Linux, including a right-clicked menu of the search bar, bookmark star, zoom lens, and some other UI logic.

Delta Electonic, Inc.Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

• Designed and built a complete system from scratch, which includes frontend, via Angular & Ant Design, and backend, via NodeJS & MongoDB. The system embodies user authorization, token mechanism, APIs, interactive interface, database, professional genome-designing module, and lots of tests, such as unit tests, end-to-end tests, and stress tests.

Fusion\$360 Taipei, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Nov 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed and developed a frontend service with Angular
- Developed crawlers for news and patents of many countries in Java, which crawls websites from Reuters, Bloomberg, and the top news websites in Taiwan, as well as the patent offices of the U.S. (USPTO), Europe (EPO), and Taiwan (TIPO).

AUGUST 29, 2021 AN-CHI LIU'S RÉSUMÉ 1